<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Books on Rupak Ganguly</title>
    <link>https://rupakganguly.com/categories/books/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Books on Rupak Ganguly</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 17:56:37 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://rupakganguly.com/categories/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Read 38 Books in 2025: Simple Habits Anyone Can Start Today</title>
      <link>https://rupakganguly.com/posts/how-i-read-38-books-in-2025-simple-habits-anyone-can-start-today/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 17:56:37 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rupakganguly.com/posts/how-i-read-38-books-in-2025-simple-habits-anyone-can-start-today/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You know that feeling when you finish a book and you just sit there for a moment, letting it all sink in? That happened to me 38 times this year. Thirty-eight books. Thirty-eight different worlds. Thirty-eight opportunities to learn something new, to be challenged, to grow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I set out to read 36 books in 2025 and surprised myself by reading 38. But here&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned over the years: it&amp;rsquo;s not really about the number. It&amp;rsquo;s about showing up, every single day, with a book in hand and curiosity in your heart.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2024 Reading Challenge: Building a Daily Reading Habit One Book at a Time</title>
      <link>https://rupakganguly.com/posts/2024-reading-challenge-building-a-daily-reading-habit-one-book-at-a-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 10:40:04 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rupakganguly.com/posts/2024-reading-challenge-building-a-daily-reading-habit-one-book-at-a-time/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I failed my reading challenge in 2024. I read 32 of 48 books. I &lt;a href=&#34;https://rupakganguly.com/posts/challenge-yourself-into-a-reading-habit/&#34;&gt;read 56 books in 2023 and challenged myself&lt;/a&gt;, and 25 books in 2022. I think I have found my sweet spot: 36 books a year, which is three books a month. I like a challenge, so I always have a stretch goal. I hope to surprise myself!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, I feel it is not about the number of books you read. It’s about the discipline and the routine to find time, to read, everyday. Even if it is 10 mins a day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are thinking of forming a good habit in 2025, start reading. I wrote about my mindset, strategies, challenges, apps, and tools on &lt;a href=&#34;https://rupakganguly.com/posts/how-to-read-24-or-more-books-in-a-year/&#34;&gt;How to Read 24 or More Books in a Year&lt;/a&gt;. Create a reading list, set a reading challenge, read every day, and track your progress. You will thank yourself later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/friend/i?feature=friend-invite-url&amp;amp;invite_token=MDU1YzMxYzktMjViYy00MTNjLTlkYjYtOGE0MDY0OTZhNzlk&#34;&gt;Be friends with me on Goodreads&lt;/a&gt;; we can share our reading lists and be each others’ accountability partners.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Challenge Yourself Into a Reading Habit</title>
      <link>https://rupakganguly.com/posts/challenge-yourself-into-a-reading-habit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 10:02:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rupakganguly.com/posts/challenge-yourself-into-a-reading-habit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of my goals every year has been to read at least two books a month, but in 2023 I challenged myself to read 3 books a month. I surprised myself, and I surpassed my expectations by reading 56 books in 2023 with an average of 4.5 books per month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2022, I wrote about &lt;a href=&#34;https://rupakganguly.com/posts/how-to-read-24-or-more-books-in-a-year/&#34;&gt;how to read 24 or more books in a year&lt;/a&gt;. I touched upon tools, apps, and ideas to keep me motivated and read more books. I talked about reading consistently throughout the year, and I found that most of us want to read, but we lack the motivation, discipline, structure, and cadence to keep reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What would it take you to go from reading zero to one book per month? Or read one more book per month?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this article, I add to my process for overcoming some hurdles to keep reading throughout the year. I hope this helps you achieve your reading goals for the upcoming year.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Read 24 or More Books in a Year</title>
      <link>https://rupakganguly.com/posts/how-to-read-24-or-more-books-in-a-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 11:55:38 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rupakganguly.com/posts/how-to-read-24-or-more-books-in-a-year/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of my goals every year has been to read at least two books a month. I have accomplished the goal by reading 25 books in 2022, and in the past years. While talking to several of my friends about reading consistently throughout the year, I found out that most of us want to read, but we lack the motivation, discipline, structure, and cadence to keep reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this article, I describe my process for overcoming some of the hurdles to keep reading throughout the year. I touch upon tools, apps, and ideas to keep us motivated and read more books. Hope this helps you achieve your reading goals for the upcoming year. Happy reading!
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>