<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Serverless on Rupak Ganguly</title>
    <link>http://rupakganguly.com/categories/serverless/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Serverless on Rupak Ganguly</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2018 11:31:26 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://rupakganguly.com/categories/serverless/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS reInvent 2018 Announcements</title>
      <link>http://rupakganguly.com/posts/aws-reinvent-2018-announcements/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2018 11:31:26 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rupakganguly.com/posts/aws-reinvent-2018-announcements/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As usual, AWS announced a slew of new services and updates to it&amp;rsquo;s existing services at reInvent 2018. Here are the most significant ones that I am maintaining a list of. I will be updating the list as more services get announced. Werner Vogels is on stage right now announcing new Serverless services and updates.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to build long-running serverless apps using Lambda and AWS Fargate with Stackery</title>
      <link>http://rupakganguly.com/posts/how-to-build-long-running-serverless-apps-using-lambda-and-fargate-with-stackery/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 16:09:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rupakganguly.com/posts/how-to-build-long-running-serverless-apps-using-lambda-and-fargate-with-stackery/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a multi-part blog series that explores building serverless applications with Stackery. In the &lt;a href=&#34;https://rupakganguly.com/posts/building-serverless-apps-using-stackery/&#34;&gt;first part&lt;/a&gt;, we discussed why Stackery is a great platform for visually building and deploying serverless applications on AWS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The application we will build is a video processing application that will take a video file dropped into a S3 bucket, along with some user-defined parameters and extract a thumbnail of the specified frame, and store it into another S3 bucket. Since the video processing bit is a long-running process, we will use AWS Fargate to process the video.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Serverless Apps Using Stackery</title>
      <link>http://rupakganguly.com/posts/building-serverless-apps-using-stackery/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2018 14:52:28 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rupakganguly.com/posts/building-serverless-apps-using-stackery/</guid>
      <description>This is a multi-part blog series that will explore building serverless application with Stackery. In this post, the first part in the series, we discuss why Stackery is a great platform for visually building and deploying serverless applications on AWS. We will also look at setting up Stackery, linking an AWS account securely with least privileges, and using a boilerplate template to build and deploy a serverless application to AWS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to build a Serverless Alexa Skill</title>
      <link>http://rupakganguly.com/posts/how-to-build-a-serverless-alexa-skill/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 17:29:03 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rupakganguly.com/posts/how-to-build-a-serverless-alexa-skill/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I was a kid, I was intrigued by the Starship Enterprise&amp;rsquo;s onboard computer featured in the science fiction series Star Trek. Although cheeky at times in it&amp;rsquo;s portrayal of technologies beyond our imagination, the voice-controlled computer always made me wonder. And, here we are in the same lifetime, realiziing similar technolgies - inside our homes, on a small device&amp;hellip; Amazing, I think! 🖖
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>