<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Business on Rupak Ganguly</title>
    <link>https://rupakganguly.com/categories/business/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Business on Rupak Ganguly</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 16:19:53 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://rupakganguly.com/categories/business/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Run a Profitable Business as a Solo Founder With AI as Your Co‑founder</title>
      <link>https://rupakganguly.com/posts/how-to-run-a-profitable-business-as-a-solo-founder-with-ai-as-your-cofounder/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 16:19:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rupakganguly.com/posts/how-to-run-a-profitable-business-as-a-solo-founder-with-ai-as-your-cofounder/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll be honest with you: when I first heard about founders running entire businesses with AI, I was skeptical. How could software replace the human touch that makes a business thrive? But here&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned—AI isn&amp;rsquo;t about replacing humanity. It&amp;rsquo;s about amplifying and complementing what one person can accomplish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For small and medium business founders like us, AI represents something revolutionary: the ability to compete with companies ten times our size without hiring a massive team. We&amp;rsquo;re living in an era where a non-technical founder can orchestrate an entire business operation from their laptop, with AI handling everything from customer inquiries to product development. This isn&amp;rsquo;t science fiction—it&amp;rsquo;s happening right now, and founders who embrace this shift early will have an enormous competitive advantage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The beauty of AI-powered business operations lies in its accessibility. You don&amp;rsquo;t need a computer science degree or a hefty budget. What you need is curiosity, willingness to experiment, and the right toolkit. Let me walk you through how different departments can be transformed by AI, and how I see this working in practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, what happens to the human factor? The conscience, the emotional intelligence, the critical decision making, the final call…
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is a Workflow Engine and its uses?</title>
      <link>https://rupakganguly.com/glossary/what-is-a-workflow-engine-and-its-uses/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 08:23:38 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rupakganguly.com/glossary/what-is-a-workflow-engine-and-its-uses/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every business has processes that follow certain work that needs to be done in a particular order, has conditional logic that can branch out work, and may involve data transformation or processing of data based on certain business rules. To facilitate the automation of such complex processing rules and logic, workflow engines and business rule engines were developed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will learn about workflow engines, different types of workflows, the components of a workflow, their benefits, and how they can be used to solve business process automation.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>