<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Glossaries on Rupak Ganguly</title>
    <link>https://rupakganguly.com/glossary/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Glossaries on Rupak Ganguly</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 08:23:38 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://rupakganguly.com/glossary/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What is a Workflow Engine and its uses?</title>
      <link>https://rupakganguly.com/glossary/what-is-a-workflow-engine-and-its-uses/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 08:23:38 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rupakganguly.com/glossary/what-is-a-workflow-engine-and-its-uses/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every business has processes that follow certain work that needs to be done in a particular order, has conditional logic that can branch out work, and may involve data transformation or processing of data based on certain business rules. To facilitate the automation of such complex processing rules and logic, workflow engines and business rule engines were developed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will learn about workflow engines, different types of workflows, the components of a workflow, their benefits, and how they can be used to solve business process automation.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is SlimAI and its benefits</title>
      <link>https://rupakganguly.com/glossary/what-is-slim-ai-and-its-benefits/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2023 23:06:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rupakganguly.com/glossary/what-is-slim-ai-and-its-benefits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Containers have been around for a while and Docker commoditized them and brought it into the hands of every developer. The usage was simple and everyone could create a Docker image and run their apps in a container. Docker Swarm and Kubernetes took it further and made it possible for us to deploy and run containerized apps at scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ease of use and small learning curve to entry for creating and running containers had their shortcomings as well. Lots of developers without a deep knowledge of operating systems, systems administration, packaging, and dependency management have been Docker images and containers without much care. This proliferated docker images and containers that had unnecessary packages &amp;amp; dependencies leading to huge image sizes and vulnerabilities. This resulted in increasing the attack surface area for security hacks and decreased performance due to large image download sizes.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is Strapi Headless CMS?</title>
      <link>https://rupakganguly.com/glossary/what-is-strapi-headless-cms/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 16:30:55 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rupakganguly.com/glossary/what-is-strapi-headless-cms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Strapi is an open-source headless CMS, and comes in three flavors: open-source Community Edition, self-hosted paid Enterprise Edition and fully managed Strapi Cloud. There is a marketplace for adding various integrations and plugins to enhance the base feature set.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is Swagger and Why It Is Used</title>
      <link>https://rupakganguly.com/glossary/what-is-swagger-and-why-it-is-used/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 18:10:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rupakganguly.com/glossary/what-is-swagger-and-why-it-is-used/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Swagger is a toolset that simplifies the design, development, documentation, and publishing of REST APIs based on OpenAPI specifications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Swagger toolset consists of open-source and paid tools: Swagger Editor, Swagger UI, Swagger Codegen, Swagger Hub, Swagger Inspector, ReadyAPI, and AlertSite.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>