<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Agenticai on Rupak Ganguly</title>
    <link>https://rupakganguly.com/categories/agenticai/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Agenticai on Rupak Ganguly</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 13:21:01 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://rupakganguly.com/categories/agenticai/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Agentic Commerce Protocol (ACP): The Future of AI-Powered Transactions</title>
      <link>https://rupakganguly.com/posts/agentic-commerce-protocol-the-future-of-ai-powered-transactions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 13:21:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rupakganguly.com/posts/agentic-commerce-protocol-the-future-of-ai-powered-transactions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Agentic Commerce Protocol (ACP)&lt;/strong&gt; is shaking up how we interact with online stores. Instead of clicking through web pages, imagine instructing an AI agent—like ChatGPT—to shop for you, handling everything from product discovery to checkout, all within a single conversation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ACP is an open standard that enables secure, seamless transactions between buyers (and their AI agents) and businesses, ensuring each party stays in control and informed throughout the process. It can let an AI agent discover products, validate availability, collect consent, and complete checkout using a retailer’s systems. The retailer is still in charge of the actual transaction details like availability, tax, fulfillment and delivery but the assistants help with the conversation and capturing the customer&amp;rsquo;s intent.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agent.ai MCP Server Integration with Claude Desktop: A Step-by-Step Tutorial</title>
      <link>https://rupakganguly.com/posts/agent.ai-mcp-server-integration-with-claude-desktop-a-step-by-step-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 14:04:50 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rupakganguly.com/posts/agent.ai-mcp-server-integration-with-claude-desktop-a-step-by-step-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this article, we will set up an Agent.ai MCP Server in Claude Desktop and explore the various possibilities MCP integration offers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Model Context Protocol (MCP) significantly advances how Large Language Models (LLMs) interact with external tools and services. At its core, MCP is a standardized communication protocol that enables AI models to seamlessly integrate with various tools, expanding their capabilities beyond basic text generation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MCP works by establishing a structured framework for tools to register their capabilities with LLMs and for LLMs to understand and utilize these tools effectively. When an LLM like Claude encounters a query that could benefit from external tools, it can identify the appropriate MCP-compatible tool, request permission to use it, and incorporate the retrieved information into its response. This creates a more dynamic and capable AI system that can access real-time data, perform complex calculations, or interact with external services.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>