<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Personal on Rupak Ganguly</title>
    <link>https://rupakganguly.com/categories/personal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Personal on Rupak Ganguly</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2023 14:17:21 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://rupakganguly.com/categories/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflections for the Year 2023</title>
      <link>https://rupakganguly.com/posts/reflections-for-the-year-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2023 14:17:21 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rupakganguly.com/posts/reflections-for-the-year-2023/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been reflecting on my past year for a few years now, but I did not publish them. This year I wanted to start the trend. Reflecting on my goals for the year, evaluating how I did, and rethinking how I spent my time. It has always provided me with clarity for the next year. Continuing what I started and starting something new has always been exciting for me, something to look forward to. Writing down the reflections, helps me see the gaps and the course corrections I need to make. It also helps me reflect on what went well, and what to improve on, and for all the things I am thankful &amp;amp; grateful for.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Better Yourself During This Covid-19 Lockdown</title>
      <link>https://rupakganguly.com/posts/how-to-better-yourself-during-this-covid-19-lockdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 21:18:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rupakganguly.com/posts/how-to-better-yourself-during-this-covid-19-lockdown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are in a terrible crisis, and it has been very stressful for everyone. Some of us are on the front lines, some of us losing our jobs, some of us are in small businesses affected by the shutdown, and some of us are forced to work from home. Kids are missing school and adapting to online learning, missing out on proms and graduations, are missing going out and playing with their friends. Some of us are juggling work from home while taking care of our children. And to top it all, fear of catching the virus and being in a precarious health situation. Chaos - to simply put it. But we as humans have survived adversities in the past and we will get over this as well. There is light at the end of the tunnel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what can we do with the situation we are in? How can we turn this adversity in our favor and make it a positive thing? How can we utilize the time we got and turn it into something productive and prepare for the future?
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excited to Join Docker</title>
      <link>https://rupakganguly.com/posts/excited-to-join-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 15:58:24 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rupakganguly.com/posts/excited-to-join-docker/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Due to a personal loss in my life, I took a few months of sabbatical to get through it. I got through the holidays with support from my family and friends. It was hard but as the year turned around, I had to move on with my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a very interesting tenure at Serverless.com and I was looking for a more close interaction with customers at large enterprises. I wanted to remain hands-on technically, but not become a code monkey. I wanted to work on a variety of enterprise use cases yet did not want to become an &amp;ldquo;on-the-road-Mon-to-Fri&amp;rdquo; consultant. I wanted to ideally work remotely and travel occasionally.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://rupakganguly.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 17:50:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rupakganguly.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Rupak Ganguly (rupakg) is a thought leader, business savvy, technology advocate, enterprise architect, and problem solver.
Over 30+ years of industry experience in architecture, design, development, and delivery of web and Windows applications on various platforms. Passionate about serverless architectures, cloud technologies, micro-services architectures, and open source; works collaboratively with team members to achieve goals; persistent &amp;amp; creative problem solver, and familiar with leading-edge development paradigms. Communicates effectively with both technical &amp;amp; business counterparts, understands business needs and creates tools to manage them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Brand</title>
      <link>https://rupakganguly.com/posts/personal-brand/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 17:29:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rupakganguly.com/posts/personal-brand/</guid>
      <description>Over the years, I have built a lot of applications and written about software and its practices. Most of the applications were internally facing and hence could not be shared in public. Many articles I wrote were hosted on internal knowledge bases or those sites have evolved. Many of those applications and writings were never made public.
Building a personal brand is crucial.
So I have decided to post all my writings here and publish all my applications on Github.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>