<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chatbots on Rupak Ganguly</title>
    <link>https://rupakganguly.com/categories/chatbots/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Chatbots on Rupak Ganguly</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 17:54:10 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://rupakganguly.com/categories/chatbots/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Comprehensive Guide to Leveraging AI Tools: From Chatbots to Code Assistants</title>
      <link>https://rupakganguly.com/posts/the-comprehensive-guide-to-leveraging-ai-tools-from-chatbots-to-code-assistants/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 17:54:10 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rupakganguly.com/posts/the-comprehensive-guide-to-leveraging-ai-tools-from-chatbots-to-code-assistants/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;AI has been the hype since Chat-GPT commoditized the use of its AI chatbot. Soon after, many AI chatbots followed suit, including Microsoft Copilot, Google Gemini, Anthropic Claude, etc. Many new applications and startups using these AI APIs sprung up as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of terminologies in play, and it gets confusing very fast. My goal has always been to make complex things easy to understand and break them into small digestible chunks that can be then delved into individually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The article&amp;rsquo;s core focus is on making AI accessible and practical for everyone, breaking down complex concepts, and emphasizing that AI is not just another tech hype but a revolutionary technology that everyone should understand. I also list some of the AI tools that I have been playing with that will give you an idea of the leverage you can get with using these tools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AI is a huge revolution, and it should not be limited to the technical folks but should be understood and leveraged by everyone.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Master AI: The Ultimate Learning Plan for Beginners (2024 Guide)</title>
      <link>https://rupakganguly.com/posts/master-ai-the-ultimate-learning-plan-for-beginners-2024-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 12:46:50 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rupakganguly.com/posts/master-ai-the-ultimate-learning-plan-for-beginners-2024-guide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is overwhelming to start anything, but getting started in a large and diverse space like AI has been challenging for many. The AI technology space is advancing at an accelerated speed, so the time to get started is now. This article is a set of recommendations, suggestions, and ideas for an AI learning plan for beginners. I hope you find this article useful if you have been wondering when and how to start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The article&amp;rsquo;s core focus is on providing a structured learning path for AI beginners, covering everything from programming fundamentals to advanced AI technologies.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>