<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Learnings on Rupak Ganguly</title>
    <link>https://rupakganguly.com/tags/learnings/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Learnings on Rupak Ganguly</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 12:46:50 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://rupakganguly.com/tags/learnings/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Master AI: The Ultimate Learning Plan for Beginners (2024 Guide)</title>
      <link>https://rupakganguly.com/posts/master-ai-the-ultimate-learning-plan-for-beginners-2024-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 12:46:50 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rupakganguly.com/posts/master-ai-the-ultimate-learning-plan-for-beginners-2024-guide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is overwhelming to start anything, but getting started in a large and diverse space like AI has been challenging for many. The AI technology space is advancing at an accelerated speed, so the time to get started is now. This article is a set of recommendations, suggestions, and ideas for an AI learning plan for beginners. I hope you find this article useful if you have been wondering when and how to start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The article&amp;rsquo;s core focus is on providing a structured learning path for AI beginners, covering everything from programming fundamentals to advanced AI technologies.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Better Yourself During This Covid-19 Lockdown</title>
      <link>https://rupakganguly.com/posts/how-to-better-yourself-during-this-covid-19-lockdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 21:18:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rupakganguly.com/posts/how-to-better-yourself-during-this-covid-19-lockdown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are in a terrible crisis, and it has been very stressful for everyone. Some of us are on the front lines, some of us losing our jobs, some of us are in small businesses affected by the shutdown, and some of us are forced to work from home. Kids are missing school and adapting to online learning, missing out on proms and graduations, are missing going out and playing with their friends. Some of us are juggling work from home while taking care of our children. And to top it all, fear of catching the virus and being in a precarious health situation. Chaos - to simply put it. But we as humans have survived adversities in the past and we will get over this as well. There is light at the end of the tunnel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what can we do with the situation we are in? How can we turn this adversity in our favor and make it a positive thing? How can we utilize the time we got and turn it into something productive and prepare for the future?
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>